<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microphone | Dylan Powers</title>
    <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/microphone/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/microphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Microphone</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 21:18:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dylandpowers.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Microphone</title>
      <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/microphone/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2021 Work From Home Setup</title>
      <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/post/my-2021-work-from-home-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 21:18:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dylandpowers.github.io/post/my-2021-work-from-home-setup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My company has allowed us to return to the office on a voluntary basis (requiring proof of vaccination). I go every day because I really value being able to discuss something easily without having to set up a Zoom meeting. Also, how could anybody possibly say no to free snacks and coffee?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the abundant nourishment, there is one thing I miss about the roughly 10 months of work-from-home that I did - my setup! I spent a lot of time researching and refining my setup, so I want to share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;monitors&#34;&gt;Monitors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For monitors, I have two 27&amp;rdquo; LG 27UL500-W 4K monitors (&lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B07PGL2WVS/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o07_s01?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;). I have them mounted using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MC9YX63/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o07_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dual arm mount&lt;/a&gt;, which allows me to move them around very easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having used both 4K and non-4K monitors, I will say that 4K is 100% worth the extra price. Even moving to a 1440p monitor feels so much different after experiencing 4K resolution for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as configuration, I have one monitor directly in front of me and one directly to the right of it, tilted toward me. Currently, both are horizontal, but I had the right one oriented vertically for about half of WFH. It was really useful for code, but I still find that it is easier to manage multiple applications when viewing them horizontally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have my laptop on the left side of my desk on a simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/dp/B00WRDS0AU/ref=twister_B011KOHEXU?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;laptop stand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mouse&#34;&gt;Mouse&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a very cheap $10 mouse for most of WFH, which treated me well. However, until I upgraded, I never knew what I was missing out on. I recently bought the Logitech MX Master 3 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B07S395RWD/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;), and it completely changed the game. The ergonomics are absolutely incredible, it&amp;rsquo;s configurable beyond belief, and it has a horizontal scroll wheel (more handy than you might think).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B0788LMLZL/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;extended mousepad&lt;/a&gt; that I also put my keyboard on. It has seen it&amp;rsquo;s fair share of spills, so it may be time to replace it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;keyboard&#34;&gt;Keyboard&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am using the Apple Magic Keyboard with an additional numeric keypad (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MQ052LL/A/magic-keyboard-with-numeric-keypad-us-english?fnode=edc42abb786ca1b7773285f06ef4610205228b9440553044f8e33d9f6aacde9535ba3fb4de8dad2b0540af00cc109e1163d4b5034aeb948dbfdc77b548cdc35bc4ae83b7561abec3b4bed8fce2bf38470ef05c57ccb31b557667784673f5319a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;). I have it in black, which matches my mouse and mouse pad exquisitely. I have thought a lot about upgrading to a mechanical soon. I ordered a switch tester (big brown fan) and will order once I feel that I have researched enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;camera&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the Logitech C922x Pro Stream Webcam (&lt;a href=&#34;https://smile.amazon.com/gp/product/B01LXCDPPK/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o09_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;) sitting on top of the monitor directly in front of me. It has excellent video quality, but the part that really surprised me is the audio quality. It comes with a built-in microphone that works incredibly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My setup is always a work in progress, but I feel that I have made a good start. There&amp;rsquo;s just a few more things that I need - plants, plants, and more plants!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
