<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intern | Dylan Powers</title>
    <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/intern/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/intern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Intern</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 17:25:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dylandpowers.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Intern</title>
      <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/tags/intern/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for a Summer in New York</title>
      <link>https://dylandpowers.github.io/post/tips-for-a-summer-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 17:25:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dylandpowers.github.io/post/tips-for-a-summer-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past summer I worked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yext.com&#34;&gt;Yext&lt;/a&gt; in New York City. Our office is located at the corner of 23rd and Madison Avenue, right next to the famous Flatiron Building, pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;flatiron.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Flatiron Building&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in New York was the best experience in my life, and I want to share some tips on how to have both a productive and fun summer in New York; I hope future interns can make use of this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-you-work-in-manhattan-live-in-manhattan&#34;&gt;If You Work in Manhattan, Live in Manhattan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made the mistake of living in Brooklyn, which made my 8-stop commute on the F train quite long. My roommate and I grabbed an Airbnb for a much cheaper price, but we still regret not living in the city. Most students live in admittedly-small dorms, but the location is &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; that matters. After a night out, taking the train home at 3am is the least appealing thing in the world, and Ubers can often break the bank. Just live in Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-plans-every-night&#34;&gt;Make Plans Every Night&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An actual conversation I had with my mentor this summer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dylan, do you have plans tonight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, not tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not? It&amp;rsquo;s New York!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I made a conscious effort to &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; find an event to go to or make plans to go to dinner with someone after work. Luckily, a fellow intern at my company compiled a calendar of free events in New York over the summer, so I just added that to my Google Calendar. If I&amp;rsquo;m only going to spend 3 months in the greatest city on Earth, I might as well make the most of it. You should too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-pigeon-for-the-subway&#34;&gt;Use Pigeon for the Subway&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pigeon.area120.com/home&#34;&gt;Pigeon&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced transit app for the subway in New York City. Not only can you plan trips and see which lines stop where, but you can also see reports of lines/stations that have problems. On July 13th, the power went out in some of Manhattan, and a lot of lines stopped running. My sister (who was visiting) and I waited in the station for twenty minutes before I finally checked Pigeon and realized what had happened. Without the app, we probably would have waited longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, be a good samaritan and post on the app! If something is going on, let people know. Good Karma pays off!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wait-for-the-train-outside-the-station&#34;&gt;Wait for the Train Outside the Station&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No joke, it&amp;rsquo;s 10-15 degrees Fahrenheit hotter in the station. The trains feel great, but the stations feel like standing in the middle of the Sahara Desert wearing a suit made out of tin foil. Get on your phone, check the arrival time on the app, and wait outside until the train is three or so minutes away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-yelp-to-find-restaurants&#34;&gt;Use Yelp to Find Restaurants&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there are so many restaurants in Manhattan, deciding what to eat feels impossible sometimes. However, whenever going out with friends, we always used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yelp.com&#34;&gt;Yelp&lt;/a&gt; to decide what to eat. It never failed once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: since you&amp;rsquo;re only there for a short time, use the 4-star or higher filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone gets the opportunity to spend a summer in New York. It really goes by quickly, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to pack as much as possible into the short time frame. Have fun in the greatest city on Earth!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
